

Skills

Power BI

PowerQuery, DAX, DataModelling, Data Visualisation

Alteryx

DataTransformation, DataModelling

SQL

SQL, Database, dbeaver, PLSQL **Business Intelligence**

businessIntelligence, businessInsights,

decisionmaking

Problem Solving

Data Analysis

Data Modelling

Data Visualization

Agile

Looker

Interests

Tableau

Photography

Digital Art

Certifications

Microsoft

Altery Designer Core

Power BI Data Analyst Associate

Alteryx

Certification

Azure Data Fundamentals Microsoft

Gold Badge on Data Visualisation

Awards

Onshore Recognition EY

Exceptional Client Service Award

EY

2023

2024

Pursuing Innovation

2023

ΕY 2022

Maveric Systems 2017

Service Strategy Award

Exceptional Client Service Award

Languages

English

Summary

\(+91 9884130081 o vigneshks93@outlook.com

Vignesh Komarapalayam Selvan

Associate Manager - Business Intelligence / Data Analytics

Linkedin

Credly

July 2024 - Now

Chennai, India

Microsoft certified Data Analyst and Business Intelligence developer with around 9 years of techno - functional experience with expertise towards Power BI and Low-Code development in Power Platform. Multifaceted experience working in Agile environments

Risk Monitoring & Supervision – JP Morgan - EY

Experience

Associate Manager Alpharetta, USA Leading an offshore team of 4 people for Risk & Monitoring Team and

responsible for the preparation of Development Strategy, Development Plan,

- Project artifacts and deliverables Leading the development of Alteryx Workflows to Extract data from different investment source systems and product directory, analyze and
- transform the data to identify the daily investment portfolio breaches for each account. Preparation of Power BI dashboard to display the various analysis and

insights based on the daily breaches by accounts and the respective daily metrics

Responsible for the development of remediation options for the customers for each breach type.

Responsible for the offshore productivity, daily and weekly reporting, and

- preparation of capacity plan for the team for every release & SPOC for the preparation and reviewing of CMMI Audit artifacts Responsible for the Code versioning, collaboration, and maintenance of
- AIR Financial Dashboard & TIPS EY March 2022 - June 2024

Leading an offshore team of 5 people for Dossier Development, responsible for the preparation of Development Strategy, Development Plan, Project artifacts

workflows and deployment in Dev, UAT and Prod environments

for the Risk & Monitoring leadership team.

Associate Manager

maintain the Data quality

activities and hinderance

templates for each Client/Project

and deliverables Leading the development of AIR Integrated Business Analysis Dashboard which provides detailed Financial and Delivery Analysis of EY global

Engagements and help Partners to understand the Commercial/Delivery - status,

- monitoring, progress, and risks at any point of time Conducted advanced analytics to identify Commercial opportunities and strengths to meet business goals Performed Data Cleansing, Data Transformation, and harmonization to
- Presented and Communicated business insights in an actionable way for business leaders from 2+ lakh engagements
- Analysis to distribute engagements based on the performance and for users to easily understand the factors contributing to the score Collaborated with data governance to ensure the Data Security and Finance

Implemented Scoring logics and calculation to build Four Quadrant

repositories Worked with Cross Functional business and technical teams to identify and integrate appropriate data sources, extract data, and develop integrated reports

teams on data quality issues, as well as architecture or structure of data

Responsible for the offshore productivity, daily and weekly reporting, and preparation of capacity plan for the team for every release & SPOC for the preparation and reviewing of CMMI Audit artifacts

Taking part in Agile ceremonies and being vocal about the on-going

- Responsible for the upgradation of TIPS (Testing Insight Platform) created using Power BI and hosted on application based on C# deployed on Azure Presented Test management data in the reports based on multiple
- for TIPS and deployment in Dev, UAT and Prod environments Dossier - EY June 2019 - March 2022

Responsible for the creation of Dossier 360 – a business analysis report to

provide 360' view of operational metrics to the Stakeholders

Responsible for the Code versioning, collaboration, and maintenance in GitHub

Integrated Utilization, Engagement, Talent, L&D and RTO data from

the stakeholders

for all the tools being prepared

Lead Consultant

various operational reports after data cleansing and transformation Responsible for the preparation of Design document and access document

Chennai, India

Implemented automatic data collection from various source locations using

Implemented scheduled refresh daily to provide up-to-date information for

Compiled business insights into presentable visuals and trend analysis with

recommendations to improve the utilization and bench management Reviewed the report with Competency leaders on a weekly basis and

presented the data to the wide group of stakeholders on Cadence call

team's clarifications and helping with the hindrances on execution

the gated process to streamline manual testing efforts

Senior Consultant Chennai, Riyadh Lead a team of 10 people for CIB T24 upgrade project and was responsible

Being a SME with respect to Power BI report development and addressing

Responsible of the identification of end-to-end business requirements and prepare technical design for the implementation

for the productivity and deliverables

Maveric Systems

April 2015 - May 2019

- Attending defect triage and taking ownership for the follow-ups and discussions regarding the defects raised by the Offshore team Established and enforced standard test processes and deliverables within
- Analyzing the CR document and Interacting with BA for clarifications if any Being responsible for the development and support of Brand-New Omni

Channel Mobile Application dashboard by taking part in user story analysis,

- Sprint planning and testing Being responsible for the implementation of Phase-I Digital Banking Dashboard
- in C# using Coded UI tool Carrying out Unit Testing and User Acceptance Testing for change request on various modules

Being part of Automation team, created scripts for Web based applications

Getting approval from Business Team and moving the CR to production release

Expert in investigating the source of issues and defects through middleware

Education

logs analysis

Loyola Institute of Business Administration

EPGP

Financial Services & IT Assurance **Anna University**

Electrical & Electronics Engineering

2010 - 2014 **Bachelor of Engineering**

Requirement Analysis **Product Management**